# Rohan French



### **Institutional Address**

Faculty of Philosophy University of Groningen Oude Boteringestraat 52 9712 GL Groningen - The Netherlands E-MAIL: rohan.french@gmail.com URL: http://rohan-french.github.io SKYPE: rohan.french

DATE OF BIRTH: January 31, 1984 NATIONALITY: Australian

AREAS OF SPECIALIZATION

Philosophical Logic • Philosophy of Logic • Metaphysics

Areas of Competence

Formal Logic • Philosophy of Language • Epistemology.

#### **CURRENT POSITION**

Jan 2015 - May 2016

Postdoctoral Researcher working with Catarina Dutilh Novaes on the "Roots of Deduction" project in the Department of Theoretical Philosophy in the Faculty of Philosophy at the University of Groningen on formal aspects of the built-in opponent conception of deduction.

#### PREVIOUS POSITIONS

2014

Visiting Research Scholar, at Center for the Advancement of Logic, its Philosophy, History & Applications and Department of Logic and Philosophy of Science, University of California Irvine. (Winter Quarter)

2013-2015

Research Assistant for Greg Restall at the University of Melbourne working on Coursera courses <a href="https://class.coursera.org/logic1-001/">https://class.coursera.org/logic1-001/</a> and <a href="https://class.coursera.org/logic2-001/">https://class.coursera.org/logic1-001/</a> and <a href="https://class.coursera.org/logic2-001/">https://class.coursera.org/logic2-001/</a>.

2011-2013

Research Associate, Department of Philosophy & Bioethics, Monash University.

## Education

#### 2007-2011

### Ph.D. in Philosophy

Department of Philosophy and Bioethics, Monash University.

- Title: "Translational Embeddings in Modal Logic"
- Degree Awarded: 17th January 2011
- Advisors: Graham Oppy, Lloyd Humberstone
- Examiners: Alasdair Urquhart (Toronto), Stephen Kuhn (Georgetown).

2002-2006

Bachelor of Arts (Hons)/Bachelor of Computer Science, Monash University

## Grants, Honors & Awards

Dean's Award for Best Sessional Teacher in the School of Philosophical, Historical and International Studies

Monash Research Graduate School Postgraduate Publication Award
 Australian Research Council (ARC) Postgraduate Research Scholarship
 Camo Jackson Award for Best Honours in Philosophy, Monash University

2005 Scholarship to attend Australian National University (ANU) Logic Summer School

## **Publications**

#### **JOURNAL ARTICLES**

2016

2015

2015

2015

2015

2013

2.009

2009

2.008

2014

2015

201X 1. French, R. "An Argument for the Ontological Innocence of Mereology", accepted for publication in *Erkenntnis*. [DOI]

2. French, R. "Structural Reflexivity and the Paradoxes of Self-Reference", Ergo, Vol.3, 113–131. [DOI]

3. French, R. and Ripley, D., "Contractions of Noncontractive Consequence Relations", Review of Symbolic Logic, Vol. 8, 506–528. [DOI]

4. French, R., "Sequent Calculi for Urn Logic", The Journal of Logic, Language and Information Vol. 24, 131–147. [poi]

5. French, R. and Humberstone, L., "An Observation Concerning Porte's Rule in Modal Logic", The Bulletin of the Section of Logic 44:1/2, 25–31.

6. French, R., "In the Mood for **S4**: The Expressive Power of the Subjunctive Modal Language in Weak Background Logics", *Studia Logica*, Vol. 103, 239–263. [DOI]

7. French, R., "Expressive Power, Mood, and Actuality", Synthese, Vol. 190, 1689–1699. [DOI]

8. French, R. (2012), "Denumerably Many Post-Complete Normal Modal Logics with Additional Propositional Constants", Notre Dame Journal of Formal Logic, Vol. 53, 549–556.[DOI]

9. French, R. (2012), "An Argument Against General Validity?", Thought, Vol. 1, 4–9.[DOI]

10. French, R. and Humberstone, L. (2009), "Partial Confirmation of a Conjecture on the Boxdot Translation in Modal logic", *Australasian Journal of Logic*, Vol. 7, 56–61.

11. French, R. (2009), "A Simplified Embedding of **E** into Monomodal **K**", *Logic Journal of the IGPL*, Vol. 17, 421–428, 2009.[DOI]

12. French, R. (2008), "The Logic of Eventual Permanence for Unending Linear Time", *The Notre Dame Journal of Formal Logic*, Vol. 49, No 2, 137–142.[DOI]

## Reviews

13. French, R., "Review of A.A. Rini and M. J. Cresswell 'The World-Time Parallel'", Australasian Journal of Philosophy, Vol. 92, 802–805. [DOI]

## In Proceedings

14. French, R. (2015), "Prover-Skeptic Games and Logical Pluralism" *Proceedings of the 20th Amsterdam Colloquium*, Edited by Thomas Brochhagen, Floris Roelofsen & Nadine Theiler, pp.128–136.

# Talks

Jun 2016	$(*) \ Melbourne, ``A Simple Sequent Calculus for Angell's \ Logic of Analytic Containment", Australasian$
	Association of Logic Conference.
Apr 2016	LMU Munich, "A Dialogical Account of Logical Pluralism", Munich Centre for Mathematical Phi-
	losophy at LMU Munich.
Apr 2016	Groningen, "A Dialogical Account of Logical Pluralism", Closing Workshop for the Roots of Deduction
	project at the University of Groningen
Dec 2015	Amsterdam, "Prover-Skeptic Games and Logical Pluralism", Amsterdam Colloquium 2015
Nov 2015	St Andrews, "Dialogue Semantics for Bilateralism: Towards a Multi-Agent Account", Workshop on
	Inferentialism at University of St Andrews.
Sept 2015	Vienna , "Prover-Skeptic Games and Logical Pluralism", Workshop on Logical Dialogue Games at
	TU Vienna.
Sept 2015	Osnabrück, "Structural Reflexivity and the Semantic Paradoxes", German Society for Analytic Phi-
	losophy (GAP.9)
Aug 2015	Helsinki, "Hypersequents for Contingent Existence", 15th Congress on Logic, Methodology and the
	Philosophy of Science.
Sept 2014	Melbourne, w. Lloyd Humberstone "Thomas Forster on Definite Descriptions", Melbourne Logic
	Group Logic Day.
May 2014	Melbourne, "Modal Logics with Statability Operators: Variations on a Priorian Theme", Melbourne
	Logic Group Logic Day.
Feb 2014	U.C. Irvine, "Predicate Logic with Explicit Scope Markers", UC Irvine Logic and Philosophy of Sci-
	ence Colloquium.
Nov 2013	Melbourne, "Predicate Logic with Explicit Scope Markers", Melbourne Logic Group Logic Day.
Nov 2012	Monash, "The Ontological Innocence of Mereology", Monash Workshop on the Metaphysics of Time. Melbourne, "Sequent Calculi for Urn Logic", Melbourne Logic Group.
Sept 2012	Sydney, "Kaplan's Monsters–The Case of Fixedly", Australasian Association of Logic Conference.
June 2012	Melbourne, "Proof Theory for Contingent Existence", Melbourne Logic Group.
June 2012	U.C. Irvine, "In the Mood for <b>S4</b> ", Invited presentation at Workshop on Actuality and Subjunctivity
Apr 2012	organised by K.F. Wehmeier.
Nov 2011	Kioloa, "The Logical Argument Against Quantifier Variance", Australian Metaphysics Conference.
Oct 2011	Monash, "The Logical Argument Against Quantifier Variance", Monash University Staff Seminar
Oct 2011	Melbourne, "Denumerably Many Post-Complete Normal Modal Logics with Additional Proposi-
OCT 2011	tional Constants", Melbourne Logic Group.
Dec 2010	Melbourne, "Expressive Power, Mood and Actuality", Melbourne Logic Group.
Oct 2007	Melbourne, "The Range of Translations and the Problem of Maximality", Melbourne Logic Group.
OCT 2007	melbourne, The Range of Translations and the Froblem of Maximanty, Melbourne Bogie Group.
	Teaching
	č
	As Lecturer
S1 2014	Lecturer for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and Paradox (University of Melbourne)

S1 2014	Lecturer for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and Paradox (University of Melbourne)
S2 2011	Guest Lecturer (Basic Modal Logic and Normal Modal Logics) for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and
	Paradox (University of Melbourne)
S2 2011	Guest Lecturer for PHIL40013 Uncertainty, Vagueness and Disagreement Honours seminar on Fatalism
	(University of Melbourne)
S2 2010	Guest Lecturer (Nozick on Skepticism) for PHL1080 Time, Self and Mind.
S1 2010	Lecturer and Course Coordinator for PHL3590 Mind and Meaning (Monash University).

#### As Tutor

Responsible for running tutorials, marking continuous assessment and exams.

S1 2014	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S2 2013	Tutor for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and Paradox (University of Melbourne).
S2 2013	Tutor for ATS1838 Philosophy: Introduction C (Logic) (Monash University).
S1 2013	Tutor for ATS2866 Symbolic Logic (Monash University).
S1 2013	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S1 2012	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S1 2011	Tutor for ATS1833 Thinking (Monash University).
S2 2010	Tutor for PHL1080 Time, Self and Mind (Monash University).
S1 2008	Tutor for PHL1030 Thinking: Analysing Arguments (Monash University)

## Service to the profession

Referee for Australasian Journal of Logic, Australasian Journal of Philosophy, Erkenntnis, Journal of Applied Non-Classical Logic, Logique et Analyse, Logic and Logical Philosophy, Logica Universalis, The Review of Symbolic Logic, Ergo, Synthese, dialectica and The Journal of Logic, Language and Information.

Reviewer for Mathematical Reviews. Reviewed items MR3339230, MR3343405, MR3234657, MR3330769, and MR3330769. .

## Referees

LLOYD HUMBERSTONE
Reader
Monash University
Clayton, Victoria, Australia

e-mail: Lloyd.Humberstone@monash.edu

Professor Greg Restall Professor University of Melbourne Parkville, Victoria, Australia e-mail: restall@unimelb.edu.au

ASSOC. PROFESSOR CATARINA DUTILH NOVAES Associate Professor University of Groningen Groningen, Netherlands e-mail: c.dutilh.novaes@rug.nl

PROFESSOR KAI F. WEHMEIER
Professor
University of California, Irvine
Irvine, California, United States of America
e-mail: wehmeier@uci.edu